Register of the Alex N. Dragnich Papers, 1859-2008
Hoover Institution Archives
Alex N. Dragnich Papers,
1859-2008
77109
Dragnich, Alex N.
80 manuscript boxes, 2 envelopes, 1 phonotape reel (33.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings, correspondence, reports, studies, memoranda, legal and government documents, diaries, newspapers, photographs, and sound recording, relating to the history, politics, and government of Serbia and Yugoslavia, relations between Croatia and Serbia, activities of the Hrvatski Domobran in the United States, the communist party of Yugoslavia, the trial of Draza Mihailovic, and Serbian émigré affairs.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1977.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Mihailovic, Draza, 1893-1946.; Hrvatski Domobran.; Savez Komunista Jugoslavije.; Croats--United States.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Yugoslavia.; Serbia--Politics and government.; Yugoslavia.; Yugoslavia--Politics and government.; Serbs--United States.; Communism--Yugoslavia.; Communism.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Armed Forces.; Phonotapes.
Biography
American political scientist; senior propaganda analyst, United States Department of Justice, 1942-1944; research analyst, United States Office of Strategic Services, 1944-1945; cultural attaché and public affairs officer, United States Embassy in Yugoslavia, 1947-1950.
Biographical Note
1912, February 22 Born, Republic, Washington
1938 BA, University of Washington (Phi Beta Kappa)
1939 MA, University of California (Berkeley)
1939 Author, The Assumptions of Democracy in the Light of Biological and Psychological Criticisms
1942-44 Senior propaganda analyst, U.S. Department of Justice
1944-45 Research analyst, U.S. Office of Strategic Services
1945 Ph.D., University of California (Berkeley)
1945 Author, The Development of Parliamentary Government in Serbia, 1869-1889
1945-47 Assistant Professor of Political Science, Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio
1947-1950 Cultural Attache and Public Affairs Officer, U.S. Embassy at Belgrade, Yugoslavia
1949 Co-author, Yugoslavia, 1949
1950-52 Associate Professor, Vanderbilt University
1952- Professor of Political Science, Vanderbilt University
1954 Author, Tito's Promised Land
1955-56 Ford Fellow, Harvard University
1956 Co-author, The Fate of East Central Europe
1958 Author, International Communism in Yugoslavia
1959-1960 Chester Nimitz Professor, U.S. Naval War College
1961 Author, Major European Governments
1966 Co-author, Government and Politics
1974 Author, Serbia, Nikola Pasic, and Yugoslavia
1979-1980 Book publications editor, Hoover Institution
1982 Author, Politics and Government
1983 Author, The First Yugoslavia
1984 Author, The Saga of Kosovo
1989 Author, Development of Parliamentary Government in Serbia
1992 Author, Serbs and Croats: The Struggle in Yugoslavia
Scope and Content of Collection
Writings, correspondence, reports, studies, memoranda, legal and government documents, diaries, newspapers, photographs, and sound recording, relating to the history, politics, and government of Serbia and Yugoslavia, relations between Croatia and Serbia, activities of the Hrvatski Domobran in the United States, the communist party of Yugoslavia, the trial of Draza Mihailovic, and Serbian émigré affairs.
Container List
- Biographical File, 1942-1986 (Box 1)
  Correspondence, reports, clippings, and printed matter relating to A. Dragnich's career. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Clippings (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum vitae (Folder 2)
  - Dragnich, George N. (Folder 3)
  - Dragnich, George S. (Folder 4)
  - Employment
    - Applications, 1945-49 (Folder 5)
    - Overseas assignment, 1962-63 (Folder 6)
    - U.S. Department of Defense, 1970-73 (Folder 7)
    - U.S. Department of Justice, 1942-46 (Folder 8)
    - U.S. Department of State, 1947-1951 (Folder 9)
  - Letters of gratitude, 1979-1986 (Folder 10)
  - Recommendations, 1962-1978 (Folder 11)
  - Trips
    - General, 1962-1980 (Folder 12)
    - Soviet Union, 1979 (Folder 13)
  - Vanderbilt University
    - Budgets and salaries, 1950-1978 (Folder 14)
    - Davis Cup matches, 1978 (Folder 15)
    - Retirement, 1978 (Folder 16)
    - Social Science building, 1970 (Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 18)
- Diaries, 1948-1949 (Box 2)
  Handwritten diaries in chronological order.
  - diaries (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1916-1988 (Boxes 2-17)
  Letters, reports, memoranda, printed material, and miscellany. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Abbott, Roger, 1947, 1956-57 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Abplanalp, H. W., 1951 (Folder 3)
  - Abrahamse, Adele, 1988 (Folder 4)
  - Abu-Jaber, Kamel, 1966 (Folder 5)
  - Adams, John C., 1956-1961 (Folder 6)
  - Aden, Jack, 1974 (Folder 7)
  - Ader, Emile, 1960-67 (Folder 8)
  - Adelman, Jonathan, 1987 (Folder 9)
  - Adler, Audrey R., 1978 (Folder 10)
  - Agnew, John, 1961 (Folder 11)
  - Aikin, Charles, 1957 (Folder 12)
  - Alexander, Lamar, 1979 (Folder 13)
  - Alexander, Stella, 1981 (Folder 14)
  - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1946 (Folder 15)
  - Alisky, Marvin, 1978 (Folder 16)
  - Allen, George V., 1951-1965 (Folder 17)
  - Allen, Richard V., 1982-83 (Folder 18)
  - Alsop, Joseph, 1952, 1956 (Folder 19)
  - Altrusa Club of Cleveland, 1946 (Folder 20)
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1959 (Folder 21)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1965-1981 (Folder 22)
  - American Committee for Liberation from Bolshevism, 1956-57 (Folder 23)
  - American Enterprise Institute, 1979 (Folder 24)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1952-55 (Folder 25)
  - American Political Science Association, 1965-1979 (Folder 26)
  - American Serbian Heritage Foundation, 1987 (Folder 27)
  - American Serbian Life Historical Research, 1986 (Folder 28)
  - Americana Annual, 1958 (Folder 29)
  - Anabtawi, Samir N., 1972-73 (Folder 30)
  - Anderle, Josef, 1976 (Folder 31)
  - Anderson, Jack, 1987 (Folder 32)
  - Andriotes, Nicolas, 1960 (Folder 33)
  - Angelich, Homer, 1980 (Folder 34)
  - Appleton-Century-Crofts, Inc., 1957 (Folder 35)
  - Archer, Laird, 1957 (Folder 36)
  - Arey, Betty, 1981 (Folder 37)
  - Arhiv Jugoslavije, 1983 (Folder 38)
  - Arizona State University, 1961-62 (Folder 39)
  - Arkansas Gazette, 1972 (Folder 40)
  - Arledge, Roone, 1984 (Folder 41)
  - Armstrong, Hamilton F. (Foreign Affairs), 1950-56 (Folder 42)
  - Ashbrook, John M., 1978 (Folder 43)
  - Assembly of Captive European Nations, 1955 (Folder 44)
  - Association of International Relations Clubs, 1952 (Folder 45)
  - Association of Serbian Combatants of the R.J.A. "Draza Mihailovich," 1981 (Folder 46)
  - Atkinson Shoe Corporation, 1959 (Folder 47)
  - Atlantic Monthly, 1951, 1981 (Folder 48)
  - Avakumovic, Ivan, 1957-1976 (Folder 49)
  - Bajcetich, Milutin, 1985 (Folder 50)
  - Baker, Howard, 1972-1982 (Folder 51)
  - Baker, John A., 1955 (Folder 52)
  - Ball, M. Margaret, 1949-1950 (Folder 53)
  - Ballis, William B., 1959 (Folder 54)
  - Banac, Ivo, 1984 (Folder 55)
  - Barghoorn, Fred, 1953 (Folder 56)
  - Baricevich, Anthony, 1973 (Folder 57)
  - Barrows, David P., 1943 (Folder 58)
  - Bartley, Ernest R., 1952, 1962 (Folder 59)
  - Bass, Ross, 1964 (Folder 60)
  - Baumgarten, Erwin, 1968 (Folder 61)
  - Bayley, Beatrice, 1984 (Folder 62)
  - Bazargani, Javad, 1962 (Folder 63)
  - Beam, Jacob, 1957 (Folder 64)
  - Beer, Samuel H., 1976 (Folder 65)
  - Beko, Helen, 1952-1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Beloff, Nora, 1982-86 (Folder 2)
  - Bellows, Thomas J., 1970 (Folder 3)
  - Bellquist, Eric, 1942-1979 (Folder 4)
  - Belmont Herald, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - Bender, George H., 1947 (Folder 6)
  - Bentley, Helen D., 1986 (Folder 7)
  - Bergerson, Frederic, 1979 (Folder 8)
  - Bertsch, Gary K., 1972-1980 (Folder 9)
  - Beschloss, Michael R., 1979 (Folder 10)
  - Beth, Loren, 1963-68 (Folder 11)
  - Bevington, Virginia A., 1977-1981 (Folder 12)
  - Bialer, Seweryn, 1977 (Folder 13)
  - Bilderman, Albert D., 1953 (Folder 14)
  - Birkby, Robert, 1976-77 (Folder 15)
  - Birmingham Committee on Foreign Relations, 1967 (Folder 16)
  - Black, Cyril E., 1950-1978 (Folder 17)
  - Blakely, Thomas A., 1961 (Folder 18)
  - Blatnik, John A., 1950 (Folder 19)
  - Bodfish, Jeanne, 1953 (Folder 20)
  - Boettiger, John, 1948 (Folder 21)
  - Bogdanovic, Nikola, 1981 (Folder 22)
  - Boiter, Albert, 1967-68 (Folder 23)
  - Bolles, Blair, 1945-46 (Folder 24)
  - Bond, Robert D., 1977 (Folder 25)
  - Bone, Hugh A., 1964 (Folder 26)
  - Boorman, Howard L., 1970-71 (Folder 27)
  - Booth, Alexander G., 1956 (Folder 28)
  - Booth, David A., 1957, 1961 (Folder 29)
  - Booth, Norman G., 1947, 1953 (Folder 30)
  - Boppe, A., 1916-18 (Folder 31)
  - Bosnitch, Sava, 1973 (Folder 32)
  - Boston State College, 1979 (Folder 33)
  - Bosworth, William, 1985 (Folder 34)
  - Bowman, Heath, 1957 (Folder 35)
  - Braatoy, Bjarne, 1945 (Folder 36)
  - Bradberry, Geneva, 1980 (Folder 37)
  - Bradley, Bill, 1987 (Folder 38)
  - Brady, Leslie S., 1957 (Folder 39)
  - Brady, Linda P., 1976-1980 (Folder 40)
  - Brandt & Brandt, 1953 (Folder 41)
  - Branscomb, Harvie, 1949-1987 (Folder 42)
  - Bratstvo, 1975 (Folder 43)
  - Brant, Irving, 1946 (Folder 44)
  - Braunovich, Drasko, 1983 (Folder 45)
  - Bravo, Robert, 1969-1970 (Folder 46)
  - Brigance, Beverly, 1954 (Folder 47)
  - Briggs, Ruth, 1950 (Folder 48)
  - Broderick, William D., 1958 (Folder 49)
  - Broniarek, Zygmunt, 1958 (Folder 50)
  - Brown, Bernard E., 1961-1979 (Folder 51)
  - Brown, Cecil, 1950-54 (Folder 52)
  - Brown, Everett S., 1946 (Folder 53)
  - Browne, Mallory, 1951-52 (Folder 54)
  - Brownell, Herbert, 1953 (Folder 55)
  - Bryant, Douglas W., 1952-59 (Folder 56)
  - Brzezinski, Jerzy, 1960 (Folder 57)
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1956-1977 (Folder 58)
  - Bucci, P. Vincent, 1967-68 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Buchanan, William, 1980 (Folder 2)
  - Buck, Philip W., 1946 (Folder 3)
  - Buck, Tom, 1975 (Folder 4)
  - Buell, Emmett, 1974-75 (Folder 5)
  - Buffalo State University (Amherst), 1967-68 (Folder 6)
  - Burbank, Kershaw, 1951 (Folder 7)
  - Burdette, Franklin L., 1954 (Folder 8)
  - Burks, Richard V., 1965, 1985 (Folder 9)
  - Bushkoff, Leonard, 1965-1979 (Folder 10)
  - Buss, Claude, 1946 (Folder 11)
  - Buttles, Bruce, 1951-1961 (Folder 12)
  - Byrnes, Robert F., 1958-1961 (Folder 13)
  - Cairns, Phyllis, 1984 (Folder 14)
  - California Institute of International Studies, 1981 (Folder 15)
  - Californiensis, Demetrius, 1978 (Folder 16)
  - Calvani, Terry, 1984 (Folder 17)
  - Campbell, Ernest Q., 1973 (Folder 18)
  - Campbell, John C., 1950 (Folder 19)
  - Canadian Review of Studies in Nationalism, 1972 (Folder 20)
  - Cannon, Cavendish, 1951-53 (Folder 21)
  - Carlisle, Douglas, 1958-1966 (Folder 22)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1946-1980 (Folder 23)
  - Carpenter, Ann M., 1980 (Folder 24)
  - Carpenter, Willard, 1963 (Folder 25)
  - Carter, Gwendden, 1957-59 (Folder 26)
  - Carver, Elizabeth, 1950-59 (Folder 27)
  - Castleberry, H. Paul, 1964-68 (Folder 28)
  - Ceramiloc, D., 1980 (Folder 29)
  - Cesnik, Paul, 1985 (Folder 30)
  - Childs, Marquis, 1951-53 (Folder 31)
  - Chiperfield, Robert B., 1953 (Folder 32)
  - City Club (Cleveland), 1953 (Folder 33)
  - Clark, Chris, 1980 (Folder 34)
  - Clark, D. G., 1953 (Folder 35)
  - Clarke, James F., 1952-54 (Folder 36)
  - Clifford, Bob, 1953-54 (Folder 37)
  - Cole, Kenneth C., 1957 (Folder 38)
  - Cole, R. Taylor, 1950-1975 (Folder 39)
  - Coleman, A. P., 1947-1954 (Folder 40)
  - Collier's, 1951 (Folder 41)
  - Collins, Elizabeth, 1985 (Folder 42)
  - Colvin, Milton, 1958-1981 (Folder 43)
  - Colvin for Congress Fund, 1960 (Folder 44)
  - Commentary, 1985-87 (Folder 45)
  - Committees on Foreign Relations, 1966-67 (Folder 46)
  - Community Service Council (Fort Lauderdale), 1961 (Folder 47)
  - Conference Board of Associated Research Councils (Washington, D.C.), 1958 (Folder 48)
  - Connelly, Bernard C., 1955 (Folder 49)
  - Constan, Peteri, 1952-54 (Folder 50)
  - Cook, Samuel, D., 1961, 1975 (Folder 51)
  - Cook, Thomas I., 1954 (Folder 52)
  - Coons, Arthur G., 1946 (Folder 53)
  - Cooper, Pam, 1977-1980 (Folder 54)
  - Cordon, Guy, 1954 (Folder 55)
  - Cosic, Dobrica, 1975-1981 (Folder 56)
  - Cosmos Travel Bureau, 1963 (Folder 57)
  - Cottrell, Dorothy A., 1957 (Folder 58)
  - Council of Serbian Organizations of Greater Cleveland, 1974-75 (Folder 59)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1954-1978 (Folder 60)
  - Crabb, Cecil Van, 1952-56 (Folder 61)
  - Crane, Phil, 1985 (Folder 62)
  - Crawford, Jean, 1987 (Folder 63)
  - Crawford, Meredith, P., 1956 (Folder 64)
  - Creer, Leland H., 1947 (Folder 65)
  - Cross, James E., 1954 (Folder 66)
  - Cubrilo, F. D., 1964 (Folder 67)
  - Czap, M., 1959 (Folder 68)
  - Daily, L. E., 1957 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Dalhousie University, 1971 (Folder 2)
  - Daly, Matther J., 1986 (Folder 3)
  - Dangerfield, Royden, 1953 (Folder 4)
  - Daughtery, Martha C., 1975 (Folder 5)
  - Davidovic, Branko, 1952 (Folder 6)
  - Davidson, Alfred E., 1959 (Folder 7)
  - Davidson, Philip, 1956 (Folder 8)
  - Davis, John A., 1957 (Folder 9)
  - Davis, Malcolm W., 1946 (Folder 10)
  - Davis, R. Allen, 1947 (Folder 11)
  - Davis, Vincent, 1964, 1976 (Folder 12)
  - Davis, Virginia K., 1959 (Folder 13)
  - Dawson, Raymond, 1961 (Folder 14)
  - Days Inns, 1977 (Folder 15)
  - Deak, Istvan, 1986 (Folder 16)
  - Dean, Gillian, 1979 (Folder 17)
  - Dellin, L. A. D., 1958 (Folder 18)
  - De Long, Gladys, 1950-53, 1965 (Folder 19)
  - Denbo, Bruce, 1954 (Folder 20)
  - Denison University (Granville, Ohio), 1969-1970 (Folder 21)
  - Deretich, Yovan, 1980 (Folder 22)
  - Derwinski, Edward J., 1985 (Folder 23)
  - Diamant, Alfred, 1965 (Folder 24)
  - Dickinson, V. Earl, 1987 (Folder 25)
  - Dimitrijevic, Marta, 1950, 1955 (Folder 26)
  - Djilas, Milovan, 1968 (Folder 27)
  - Djordjevic, Dimitrije, 1971-77 (Folder 28)
  - Djordjevic, Miroslav, 1970, 1974 (Folder 29)
  - Djukic, Ana, 1969-1971 (Folder 30)
  - Dokich, Jovo, 1953 (Folder 31)
  - Dolan, Eleanor F., 1948, 1960-61 (Folder 32)
  - Dole, Bob, 1983 (Folder 33)
  - Donaldson, Robert H., 1973-1985 (Folder 34)
  - Dorland, G. M., 1957 (Folder 35)
  - Dorsey, John T., 1980 (Folder 36)
  - Dr. Lazo M. Kostich Fund, 1981 (Folder 37)
  - Drachkovitch, Milorad M.
    - 1956-1981 (Folder 38)
    - 1971-1977 (Folder 39)
  - Dragnic, Milorad, 1967-1980 (Folder 40)
  - Dragnich Corovic, Rose, 1975 (Folder 41)
  - Drake University (Des Moines, Iowa), 1946 (Folder 42)
  - Draskovich, Slobodan, 1956-1981 (Folder 43)
  - Dron, John A., 1943-1980 (Folder 44)
  - Dudas, Kathy, 1978-79 (Folder 45)
  - Dugan, Arthur, 1955 (Folder 46)
  - Dumbarton Oaks Trustees for Harvard University, 1976-77 (Folder 47)
  - Dunham, Donald C., 1957 (Folder 48)
  - Dunn, Winfield, 1971 (Folder 49)
  - Durham, G. Homer, 1961 (Folder 50)
  - Durrell, Lawrence, 1961-1986 (Folder 51)
  - Dustmann, Walter H., 1949 (Folder 52)
  - Dwyer, T. L., 1957 (Folder 53)
  - Dzambazovic, Radivoje, 1987 (Folder 54)
  - Earhart Foundation, 1969-1981 (Folder 55)
  - East Europe (New York), 1969 (Folder 56)
  - Eisenbach, Charles R., 1960 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Eisert, Bill, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Emeritus Institute, 1979 (Folder 3)
  - Epstein, Fritz T., 1950, 1967 (Folder 4)
  - Erickson, Jack, 1949 (Folder 5)
  - Estey, J. A., 1946 (Folder 6)
  - Eulau, Heinz, 1944-47 (Folder 7)
  - Evans, Dan, 1988 (Folder 8)
  - Farringer and Company, 1969 (Folder 9)
  - Federal Communications Commission, 1975 (Folder 10)
  - Feeley, Tom, 1958 (Folder 11)
  - Felman, Richard L., 1982 (Folder 12)
  - Felts, Richard, 1978 (Folder 13)
  - Ferry County Treasurer, 1955, 1977 (Folder 14)
  - First Serbian Benevolent Society, 1980 (Folder 15)
  - Fischer-Galati, Stephen, 1979-1981 (Folder 16)
  - Fisk University, International Student Center, 1953 (Folder 17)
  - Flathman, Richard E., 1964 (Folder 18)
  - Fleming, D. F., 1951-55, 1966 (Folder 19)
  - Fleming, Horace, 1978-1980 (Folder 20)
  - Flood, Daniel J., 1955 (Folder 21)
  - Ford, Franklin L., 1955-56 (Folder 22)
  - Foreign Affairs, 1980-88 (Folder 23)
  - Foreign Books Company, 1979 (Folder 24)
  - Foreign Policy, 1987 (Folder 25)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1947 (Folder 26)
  - Foster, Charles A., 1953 (Folder 27)
  - Fotitch, C., 1955-57 (Folder 28)
  - Fotitch, Tatiana, 1969 (Folder 29)
  - Fox, Bette D., 1973-1980 (Folder 30)
  - Franges, Oton, 1954 (Folder 31)
  - Free Serbian Orthodox Diocese, 1985 (Folder 32)
  - Freedom For Captive Nations Committee, 1960 (Folder 33)
  - Freeman, J. Leiper, 1955, 1962-64 (Folder 34)
  - French, Robert W., 1957 (Folder 35)
  - Frey, Cynthia, 1977 (Folder 36)
  - Friar, G. Edward, 1957 (Folder 37)
  - Friedberg, Maurice, 1970 (Folder 38)
  - Fuller, C. Dale, 1955 (Folder 39)
  - Fulton, Richard H., 1964-1985 (Folder 40)
  - Gakovich, Robert P., 1980 (Folder 41)
  - Gallagher, John F., 1957 (Folder 42)
  - Gange, John, 1961 (Folder 43)
  - Gaus, John M., 1958 (Folder 44)
  - Gauthier-Finnbogason, Simmonne, n.d. (Folder 45)
  - Gehlen, Michael P., 1942 (Folder 46)
  - George, 1962 (Folder 47)
  - Georgescu-Roegen, Nicholas, 1967-1988 (Folder 48)
  - Georgevich, Dragoslav, 1986-88 (Folder 49)
  - Gerard de la Villesbrunne, 1963 (Folder 50)
  - Gibbs, Judy, 1972 (Folder 51)
  - Gillette, Guy, 1952 (Folder 52)
  - Glasnik, 1983 (Folder 53)
  - Glassford, Margaret, 1951-52 (Folder 54)
  - Glick, Edward M., 1947 (Folder 55)
  - Glouchevitch, M., 1969-1970 (Folder 56)
  - Goodman, William, 1965, 1968 (Folder 57)
  - Goodspeed, S. S., 1948, 1961 (Folder 58)
  - Goss, Hilton, 1953-1961 (Folder 59)
  - Govorchin, Gerald, 1959 (Folder 60)
  - Gracy, Brainard, 1957 (Folder 61)
  - Graham, George J., 1973-1988 (Folder 62)
  - Graham, Malbone, 1942 (Folder 63)
  - Grant, Daniel R., 1957-1977 (Folder 64)
  - Grdjich, Radmilo, 1956 (Folder 65)
  - Green, James, 1980 (Folder 66)
  - Greene, Lee S., 1957 (Folder 67)
  - Gregory, Martha, 1978 (Folder 68)
  - Grgurevich, Sonja, 1953 (Folder 69)
  - Griffin, S. Randall, 1979 (Folder 70)
  - Grigis, Alfred, 1952-54 (Folder 71)
  - Grodzins, Morton, 1952-53 (Folder 72)
  - Groenen, Jan, 1957, 1962-66 (Folder 73)
  - Gustafson, Randyi, 1976 (Folder 74)
  - Guadalupe Hotel (Mexico), 1967 (Folder 75)
  - Guthrie, Warren, 1952 (Folder 76)
  - Gyorgy, Andrew, 1958-1967 (Folder 77)
  - Hall, Leonard, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Hallowell, John H., 1954-57 (Folder 2)
  - Halperin, Ernest, 1957 (Folder 3)
  - Halpern, Joel, 1956 (Folder 4)
  - Hamerow, Professor, 1985 (Folder 5)
  - Hamilton College (Clinton, NY), 1961-62 (Folder 6)
  - Hammer, J. Richard, 1958-59 (Folder 7)
  - Hammond, Thomas T., 1954 (Folder 8)
  - Harbordt, Edwin M., 1949-1950 (Folder 9)
  - Harcourt, Brace, Jovanovic, Inc., 1958-1988 (Folder 10)
  - Harper's magazine, 1951-52 (Folder 11)
  - Harris, Robert J., 1954-1967 (Folder 12)
  - Hart, Ray L., 1970-1981 (Folder 13)
  - Hartman, Paul J., 1965 (Folder 14)
  - Hartmann, Frederick H., 1957 (Folder 15)
  - Harvard University
    - Faculty Club, 1955 (Folder 16)
    - Russian Research Center, 1961 (Folder 17)
    - U.S. Air Force. R.O.T.C. 1956 (Folder 18)
  - Hass, Edward, 1954 (Folder 19)
  - Hatt, Paul K., 1946 (Folder 20)
  - Havard, William, 1980 (Folder 21)
  - Haynes, Lloyd A., 1950 (Folder 22)
  - Heard, Alexander, 1951-1987 (Folder 23)
  - Heckman, Dayton E., 1946-1951 (Folder 24)
  - Heckscher, August, 1958 (Folder 25)
  - Hehn, Paul N., 1968 (Folder 26)
  - Heim, Peggy, 1965 (Folder 27)
  - Heimberger, Frederic, 1946 (Folder 28)
  - Heimlich, William F., 1958-59 (Folder 29)
  - Hemingway, W. L., 1953 (Folder 30)
  - Henricksen, S., 1953 (Folder 31)
  - Heritage Foundation, 1979 (Folder 32)
  - Herring, Pendleton, 1952 (Folder 33)
  - Hillsboro High School (Nashville), 1957-59 (Folder 34)
  - Hilsman, Roger, 1962 (Folder 35)
  - Hilton, Ronald, 1981-85 (Folder 36)
  - Hodge, Philip G., 1950 (Folder 37)
  - Hoffman, George W., 1977 (Folder 38)
  - Hogsed, Robert A., 1960-61 (Folder 39)
  - Holmes, Stetson, 1953-54 (Folder 40)
  - Hoover Institution, 1965-1988 (Folder 41)
  - Hope, Guy A., 1969 (Folder 42)
  - Hoptner, Jacob B., 1965-66 (Folder 43)
  - Hornsby, Charles, 1968 (Folder 44)
  - Hotz, Alfred H., 1967 (Folder 45)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1961 (Folder 46)
  - Houtz, Philip, 1954 (Folder 47)
  - Howard, Harry N., 1941 (Folder 48)
  - Howell-Jones, David, 1965 (Folder 49)
  - Humbolt State College, 1964-65 (Folder 50)
  - Humphrey, Hubert, 1958 (Folder 51)
  - Hungarian Association of Indianapolis, 1958 (Folder 52)
  - Hunt, Bette, 1982 (Folder 53)
  - Hunt, William, 1962-1981 (Folder 54)
  - Hurwitz, Jake, 1974-76 (Folder 55)
  - Huston, James A., 1960-1970 (Folder 56)
  - Huth, Carl F., 1946-47 (Folder 57)
  - Huyler, Coulter D., 1952 (Folder 58)
  - Hyneman, Charles S., 1945 (Folder 59)
  - Ingram Corporation, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Ingram, E. Bronson, 1977 (Folder 2)
  - Inlow, E. Burke, 1946, 1962-69 (Folder 3)
  - Institute of International Education, 1955-56 (Folder 4)
  - International Club of Washington, D.C., 1968-69 (Folder 5)
  - International Political Science Association, 1954 (Folder 6)
  - Ivanovich, Vera, 1950-1960 (Folder 7)
  - Jackson, Henry M., 1954-1980 (Folder 8)
  - Jacobs, Dan W., 1974 (Folder 9)
  - Jakovljevic, Milan, 1971 (Folder 10)
  - Janner, Greville, 1976 (Folder 11)
  - Jelavich, Charles, 1950-1962 (Folder 12)
  - Jennings, W. Ivor, 1954 (Folder 13)
  - Jewish Community Center (Nashville), 1957-59 (Folder 14)
  - Jewish Welfare Federation, 1950 (Folder 15)
  - Jocich, Vlasta, 1956 (Folder 16)
  - Johnson, Edward, 1955 (Folder 17)
  - Johnson, Helen, n.d. (Folder 18)
  - Johnson, Walter, 1953-55 (Folder 19)
  - Johnston, Mary, n.d. (Folder 20)
  - Johnstone, William C., 1954-1960 (Folder 21)
  - Jonas, Frank H., 1950-1977 (Folder 22)
  - Jonasson, J. A., 1954, 1961 (Folder 23)
  - Jonasson, Steine, 1979 (Folder 24)
  - Jones, Victor, 1957 (Folder 25)
  - Jordan, Charlotte, 1976 (Folder 26)
  - Jordan, David C., 1972-75 (Folder 27)
  - Jossey-Bass, Inc., Publishers, 1966 (Folder 28)
  - Journal of Politics, 1980 (Folder 29)
  - Jovanovic, Tomira, 1954 (Folder 30)
  - Junker, Carl, 1954 (Folder 31)
  - Jurika, Stephen, 1976 (Folder 32)
  - Kajevich, Steven N., 1976 (Folder 33)
  - Kammerer, Gladys M., 1959 (Folder 34)
  - Karanovich, Milenko D., 1976-79 (Folder 35)
  - Karganovich, Stephen, 1979 (Folder 36)
  - Karlo, Milan, 1980 (Folder 37)
  - Karpat, Kemal, 1961 (Folder 38)
  - Kash, R. C., 1972 (Folder 39)
  - Kassof, Allen H., 1987 (Folder 40)
  - Kefauver, Estes, 1953-1963 (Folder 41)
  - Keller, George M., 1947 (Folder 42)
  - Kelly, Marie, 1978 (Folder 43)
  - Kemp, Jack, 1987 (Folder 44)
  - Keohane, John, 1984 (Folder 45)
  - Kerekes, Tibor, 1958 (Folder 46)
  - Kerner, Robert J., 1942-47 (Folder 47)
  - Kertesz, Stephen D., 1956 (Folder 48)
  - Kessel, John H., 1976 (Folder 49)
  - Ketcham, Betty, 1950-51 (Folder 50)
  - King, Lorna M., 1954-55 (Folder 51)
  - King, William B., 1954 (Folder 52)
  - Kirka, Danica, 1984 (Folder 53)